Rica Mae Lacson

Associate Software Engineer

Sta. Cruz Parian Mexico Pampanga +639776929834 lacsonrica@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced Software Developer and Quality Engineer with knowledge of ETL Development, Cloud Computing, Quality Management Systems, and Application Development Support. Maintained a good stand-in delivering quality output for client's satisfaction while maintaining industry standards.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Don Honorio Ventura State University

Bacolor, Pampanga

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering 2013–2018 Class President

SKILLS

- Informatica PowerCenter
- UNIX Scripting
- Oracle SQL
- AWS Cloud
- Front-end Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Software Testing
- JIRA
- Python

CERTIFICATION

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (2021–2024)
- AWS Certified Developer Associate (2021-2024)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (2021–2024)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (Accenture)

December 2020-Present

Project #2: Printing Company | America Fortune 500

Role: ETL Developer

Tools: Informatica PowerCenter, Toad for Oracle and Analysts, UNIX Scripting, JIRA

Description:

- >Participates in ETL Design of new and existing mappings workflows with the team and prepared technical specifications.
- >Developed ETL mappings using Informatica PowerCenter and prepare corresponding documentation.
- >Implements versioning of the ETL repository and supporting code as necessary
- >Develops stored procedures, database triggers, and SQL queries where needed.
- >Implements best practices and tunes SQL code for optimization.
- >Participates in Code review and UAT Testings.

Project #1: International Financial Insurance Company **Role:** Application Support Engineer

Tools: Informatica PowerCenter, Oracle SQL Developer, and DBMoto

Description:

- >Interpret data, analyze results using SQL Developer, DBMoto, and Informatica PowerCenter to provide ongoing reports.
- >Develop and implement databases, data collection systems, data analytics, and other strategies that optimize efficiency and quality.
- >Acquire data from primary or secondary and maintain databases/data systems.
- >Work with management to prioritize business and information needs.

QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER (Kodec Precision Inc.)

August 2019 - November 2020

- >Establish and maintain Quality Management Systems in Production.
- >Prepare regular Quality Reports such as QAN, 8D Reports, FMFA
- >Develop and monitor performance metrics for all processes in the Production.